How do you ensure that an interview is
effective? Not like this. So, if you go
there
and you tell them, "You should be
completely honest. Tell us what you
think about the product or tell us what
you think about this problem. Tell us
what you think about your day, but just
so you know, we are losing all of our
nights, all of our weekends, all of our
money. We don't have a salary. We don't
have what to eat. We're struggling.
Please tell us it's a good idea."
Don't do that. You need
reality. You don't need
lies from
these sort of interviews. So, you need
to you need them to be real rather than
to tell you what you like. And this is
why usually AI
that validates you and your ideas is
very tricky to use in these sort of
situations in regards to customer
discovery.
Other tips that you might use and these
are stuff that
I found during my my interviews. You
should interview one person at a time
and you should pay attention fully to
that person. It can last for, I don't
know, 30 minutes is uh quite
low as a target, but you should do 45
minutes an hour with the person
especially at the beginning so that you
have time
to do everything that you you want. You
should always prepare. So, this is very
important. You shouldn't go in an
interview with a
potential user because we are not
selling anything. They're not customers.
Okay, so we don't want to sell them
anything.
We should prepare. We should have our
questions. We should at least seem
prepared and respectful of their time.
Okay?
This is the way in which you start. You
should take notes and do follow-ups
afterwards. So,
you shouldn't go there and after that
you should just call your co-founder and
and say, "Yeah, everything was nice."
They answered yes to everything. No, you
should have questions with answers. You
should do a recording. You should have a
transcript. You should put that
transcript maybe somewhere and then AI
do
an evaluation and a follow-up and a
summary for the whole team. Okay? So,
you can do this much easier now. In the
past, we did the transcript by hand. We
listened to it and did the transcript by
hand and did the summary, you know, by
hand. So, now you have the power of
doing all of this with AI. So, please do
that and enjoy the experience of the
interview fully and do as many
interviews as you can because afterwards
you can use all of this data and cluster
it and play around with it
and discuss it with the whole team in a
much easier fashion.
You should try to kill your idea.
So, this is the best way in which you
can go right now
to do customer discovery. So, you should
push it to the max. If it doesn't die in
this customer interviews,
that means it's you should move forward
with it. And just so you know, mentors
and everyone in innovation labs are not
evil. They're not asking you questions
because they hate you in some way and
they don't trust you with your idea.
They're actually trying to kill it
because they're trying to do well by you
and kill it or actually tell you how it
can be killed or what you can validate
or invalidate early on because mentors
see patterns. They've seen some things.
They have their questions in their mind.
So, everything that they say, everything
that they ask you,
you should use as things to validate, as
hypotheses to validate. Even though you
don't know how to answer,
uh you need to go there and validate all
of those things, okay?
You should ask open-ended questions and
ask for clarifications.
You should never, ever ask a question
that can be answered by yes or no.
So, that's why "Do you like this
product?" is a wrong question because it
can be only yes because no one will tell
you no.
You should ask, "How does your work day
go? How do you do that specific flow?
Uh what applications you have on your
computer and how do you use them? What
apps do you pay for every month? Do you
play any games? Um
does your Do Do your children use any
any apps? Do you blah blah?" Okay? So,
you're validating
a problem space, uh and you are asking
questions that are open so that people
can open up in front of you and tell you
the whole context.
You shouldn't lead them on. So, you
shouldn't ask leading questions. You'll
notice quite fast when your questions
are leading because they will answer
what you expect them to.
The right questions, when they are not
leading, you will never know what they
might answer and they have the
opportunity to tell you something that
will hurt you.
So, that's why you shouldn't lead them
towards your
um
wanted answer. You shouldn't sell. So,
in customer interviews, in customer
discovery in general, the point is not
selling.
Is to validate assumptions. And don't
pitch it because
it's it's not the point. You are
validating the problem so that you build
that specific solution. You are not
pitching it uh there.
Selling and pitching is done by other
people, not uh
who you are in customer discovery. You
need to wear other hats.
Everyone lies.
That is unfortunate, but true. You need
to dig deeper. Uh in time, you will um
realize uh how this works, and you will
feel when people are not telling you
everything. But usually, the first
uh things that they say uh is um things
that make them feel good or make them um
escape you faster.
So, in general, you need to make it um
be a discussion so that they tell you
like they tell a friend, but about their
job.
You should choose a neutral and quiet
environment. No one can talk
when they have noises around, and it
should be neutral in the sense of it
shouldn't be an
interrogation.
And customers do not know everything.
So, you shouldn't expect that they know
what you should build. They know about
their lives, their their uh ways of
working, their
uh day in life.
Uh so, they they don't know what you
should build for them to solve their
problems. Only you can define that,
because if they would know, they would
build it for themselves.
You should maintain a beginner's
mindset. So, you shouldn't be arrogant
or seem like you know better.
Even though maybe in some contexts with
users,
um they might be from another industry.
They might not know tech.
So, but you should maintain a beginner's
mindset with their industry, with what
they're doing, because they, if they're
open and they you don't seem like the
smartest in the room and you listen to
them,
uh then they will tell you exactly how
their uh, industry works, how their work
works. You should create a conversation,
not an interrogation. You shouldn't ask
them what they want from you, because
guess what? Again, they don't know.
Because if they would have known, they
would have built it themselves.
And you should spend time with users
often.
This should be, I don't know, every
week. You should spend time with users.
You should understand them.
And avoid yes or no questions, and don't
look for
approval. Look for insights. So, this is
how we call things that we get out of
this whole uh, interview process. We
look for insights, okay? And those
insights we analyze and we transform
into
uh, hypothesis validation or
invalidation. You should uh, look at the
Mom Test. It There's a book, but there
are also videos that you can search for.
And you should look at this so that you
know um,
better how to uh,
do customer interviews. I cannot explain
it better than this. It's like the best
way to to get your info.